To explain how this works,
要解释这个的原理
I have to talk about high-dimensional Gaussians.
我需要讲解下高维高斯函数
These are often called Multivariate Gaussians.
通常称之为多元高斯函数
The mean is now a vector with one element for each of the dimensions.
均值现在是向量 每个维度对应一个元素
The variance square is replaced by what's called a covariance and it's a matrix
方差变成协方差 它是一个矩阵
with D rows and D columns if the dimensionality of the estimator is D,
如果估计函数的维度是 D 则有 D 行和 D 列
and the formula is something you have to get used to.
公式比较复杂
I'm writing it out for you,
是这样的
but you'll never get to see this again.
但是你不会再见到这个公式了
Pay the tooth even I have to look up the formula for this class,
说实话 连我都要查询一下这个公式
so I don't have it in my head and please don't get confused.
我也没记住 不用担心的
Let me explain it to you more intuitively.
我更直观地解释下
Here's a two-dimensional space.
这是一个二维空间
A two-dimensional Gaussian is defined over that space
在该空间定义了一个二维高斯函数
and it is possible to draw the contour lines of the Gaussian that might look like this.
可以画出该高斯函数的等高线 看起来可能这样
The mean of this Gaussian is this x_0,
该高斯函数的均值是 (x_0,y_0)
y_0 pair and the covariance now
协方差定义的是高斯函数的分散情况
defines the spread of the Gaussian as indicated by these contour lines.
如这些等高线所示
A Gaussian with small amounts of uncertainty might look like this.
不确定性低的高斯函数看起来可能这样
It may be possible to have a fairly small uncertainty in
有可能一个维度的不确定性很低
one dimension but a huge uncertainty in the other.
另一个维度的不确定性很高
The uncertainty in the x dimension is small and the y dimension is large,
例如 x 维度的不确定性低 y 维度的不确定性高
and when the Gaussian is tilted as shown over here,
当高斯函数倾斜时 如此图所示
then the uncertainty of x and y is correlated which
则 x 和 y 的不确定性是相关联的
means if I get information about x that actually sits over here,
表示如果我获得位于此处的 x 的信息
they would make me believe that y probably sits somewhere over here.
则我会认为 y 可能位于此处
That's called correlation.
称之为相关性
I can explain to you the entire effect of estimating velocity and using
我可以解释下估算速度
it in filtering using Gaussians like this and it becomes really simple.
并使用高斯函数根据速度进行过滤的过程 实际上非常简单
The problem I'm going to choose is a one-dimensional motion example.
我将介绍的问题是一个一维动作示例
Let's assume at t equals 1,
假设 t = 1
we see our options over here,
对象在这里
at t equals 2 right over here,
t = 2 时在这里
at t equals 3 over here,
t = 3 时在这里
then you would assume that at t equals 4,
然后你会认为当 t = 4 时
the object sits over here.
对象在这里
And the reason why you would assume this is even
这么认为的原因是
though we just seen these different discrete locations,
即使我们只看到了这些不同的离散位置
you can infer from where there's actually velocity that drives
但是可以推断有个速度
the object to the right side to the point over here.
促使对象移到右侧的这个位置
Now, how does the Kalman Filter addresses?
卡尔曼滤波器是如何处理此问题的？
This is the true beauty of the Kalman filter 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
这才是卡尔曼滤波器的真正精彩之处. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6